26, while the invocation by Sister Barchefe, Mr. Shana Mood.
Father God, we come before you today during this meeting, which is to ask that you may just use us,
direct us on the right path. Father, we just ask that you, our decisions are made to glorify you.
We thank you for the city that we serve, the community within it.
And we just thank you for your sacrifice and your Jesus Heavenly Name, we pray.
Amen.
When we get to the right of the United States of America, and to the Republic for which it stands,
one nation, another nation, another nation, and a new visible, with liberty and justice for all.
Four people to give, but let's get to the personal taxes, we have none.
Five.
Five A, claim to list.
Lunchable proof.
Say it.
Five.
Second.
See, vote on the city of Manila Merci Operations Plan.
Linda.
Good evening.
Hopefully y'all have had an opportunity to read the 36-page long thing.
It was 102 pages.
We condensed it down.
Kiri and I have been working on it.
It's basically what keeps us and you guys in a continuity of government.
When we have a disaster.
Manmade or natural.
Misty has reviewed it and kind of gave her blessing to it.
What it is is, upon y'all approval, we will send it to a calming emergency management.
They will keep it on fire.
It's basically something that keeps us going when we have a disaster.
It tells you guys what you have to do.
What I have to do and what the departments are required to do during a disaster.
If y'all have any questions, it will be updated.
It hasn't been updated since 2013.
But why is normally this is not going to be updated like this again because when a council position changes or city manager, what we will do is we will get with the new person, have them read it.
They will sign off.
We don't have to go through this whole.
Great.
area again. It's basically we've updated it just because it hadn't been updated in year
two. Another song page six is where it does require all of our signatures. Are you going
to be able to update that? The band will be well if you go to the next page and it says record
of revisions and changes. That's where we will do the number change. It'll be number one
data changes whenever and it'll be the basic plan and changes made and it will be whoever
goes off the council or comes on the council but it's only the council that we will do it for
although MSUA, the council in my PFA, it's on all three agendas because it will affect those three
agendas or those three boards, authorities because if we go into disaster each of those
boards will have if we have to book. Here's something we have to purchase something. You guys
are the ones that will approve that in that fashion for that board or authority for council. Does that
make sense? And then it will be emailed to each one even though I have a signature for the recipient
of the email so they don't have to deal with the approval page. We will do that when we do a
change as well as a revision on page seven. I'll make a motion. 5D resolution MSUA 2026 that's year two
and CC 2026 that's year five for transportation alternatives grant project application and maintenance
commitment. Yes, good evening board. This is for a tap grant for a lot of tap grant. So the last time we
did tap grant, we did the last phase on Main Street if you remember. I think bus is just coming on this
mayor. You finished up the last phase of the Main Street project. This tap grant will be going for some
sidewalking improvements. So we will go from if you notice we have sidewalking that goes on central. We will
continue that on to this pool. So to the middle school high school and then from central to Rockville
will actually have a sidewalking. It goes between those two as well. So we have like a day
serious court. Yes. And then uh
Also, we would be improving some of the sidewalks down on A Street, but it's always bothering me when I drive through town and on my streets
And I look at the sidewalks and they're like, so we're there cracked, they're spawning, different things like that
So that's what this grandma does for us. So it's part of the grant package
We have to approve a resolution showing that we will match so it's about Jimmy and all project
And so we get a naturally percents or a group in a little match
I mean, we have somebody set aside to do some different side of the term anyway, so we'll put that money in
Do that
Except from central to rockdale
Yes, so we'll connect to the
But where is it in that rockdale? Because there's nothing
What would it give it in and essence of any of you? So you could be in a walk around so you okay?
So you turn the corner and catch up with that sidewalk that's in there. Yes, okay
And so we will
We kind of we updated our numbers based on you know, we got to grant the female grant to raise
Almsdree so you know, we'll set it outside of the right the right for Almsdree so that it would not be effective
Or if we receive this grant for the raising their roads and everything so
We'll be on the west side
The road, Elm Street west side
I had to add a thing. Yeah, for sure the west side. Then from
From Elm to the school west side of the road beyond north or south
South
Have to be on the south
Yeah, you couldn't put it on the north
We haven't really finalized that
I mean right now I think it's on the north because it's pretty good sides right away there
But obviously we get the grant we would survey it and then they are
Engineering plans on
The drawings would make sense across the street to have to cross the street again. Yeah, what's old you
Start in the north side
On the south side by the bridge. Yeah, it's on the north side in the bridge
There goes all the bridge on the north side
I should
Not
On the north side
To the north side
And obviously we don't have the grant so I mean we've had to do the first days
They don't really took wrong away for community
So we go all the way down to Rotdale and then turn
Connect to the one that park creek bridge
Yes, we put in right there. Yeah, and then you keep going you can
Around the school
I think that's like shistly to turn back left
Like a huge loop
Since it's going
What are you drinking while you're watching but there's
There's the other side of the bridge
Yeah, we can do
I'm a visual, I'm a visual learner.
Can you tell us where I work in the arts team?
I don't know.
I don't know how to go there.
He parks in the parking lot.
Can I watch you in the evening?
I'm going to park across the field.
I want to make sure to walk around that.
I want to know where you're parked at.
I can't wait to walk in.
Really?
I can say it.
I can't wait.
Do we need a motion to approve?
Yes.
I'll make one.
Second.
Wait.
Can I?
Sorry.
Are you sitting as afterwards?
I can't.
You can't go on.
You have to have the picture start at least 20 more hours.
So if you want.
Okay.
Before you go.
Then we would have to table this other next.
Okay.
And he is okay with this building.
So I go up on there.
There's that.
There's that one.
We're just connecting.
I was actually going to pull it from the audience.
But she's talking about him.
He was properly downhill.
Right?
We just have a ride away there.
Is that right?
Sorry.
I get that.
Where the barons are?
Yeah.
We're going down there.
Oh, and then you're going up on the more side.
It's blocking.
All right.
Yeah.
Okay.
I've got to pull there.
You're like, I don't know how to tell you.
It's got you.
My bed.
I have a coffee.
Thank you.
All right.
Proud mate.
Motion.
Who's taking it?
Give it.
Good.
Hi.
Okay.
Five.
Good.
Hi.
Okay.
Five.
Good.
The tribal grant with the motops and the auto tribe for AMI system and for the water treatment
plan upgrades.
So tonight is we're wording the bids for all these items.
So, you know, the first six are related to the AMI system in the last one is the water treatment
plan.
So about every bit of water that we ship out, majority of it, I'm a size of like, I guess you can say
well, eight comes out of the plan.
Twelve is not either.
Yes.
Okay.
Let's see if our water comes out of the plan, we will do our neighbors.
Recently, there's likely to be water issues.
If you ever go down to our plan, it is very, very old.
.
some piping that I was looking at that I think like we probably should never touch because they
would come apart if you were touched. So we're very very excited about this project. As far
as the meters we've done a lot of huge research on this. I think we put in over 100 hours
on research on these different meters. This section we went with this like a best in class for
a water meter and four electric meter. Some people go with like one solution, one bender.
We decided to go two different benders. Just because we felt like this was like the boss water
meter, this was a best electric meter. And so that's kind of the way that things are set up
tonight. I'm trying to think what else. We reached out to a lot of contacts. I mean we reached
out to a broken air or a water meter. They, they submitted, really nice email that 42 or 43,000
water meters. I'm going to communicate by sailor. They said they have like a 98% read. So that's
a whole good. So you know this would be, we'd be able to read the meters in the field. The other thing is
cool is customer is about a log in and see their usage. So I know that would be really nice.
When they come in and change the meter on the side of the house, did they do it like they do now?
They just pushed it and pulled off or how they, yeah. So just, yeah. They're disconnected. They would
use it, but they break that low Vs per liter and they put it on their left. They don't have to do
any more wiring or anything like that, right? And what's the really whole year? Well there
is that possibility. If we pull a meter out and we'll get it. So Lannison gear has a really
neat feature that they have a hot socket function and that they know if those jaws and those
meter cans are getting wore out or not. So we'll work as step before we have those burning meters.
We have those occasionally now, anyways. So every time I'm in cabins to speak to that, but whenever
we change out meter for coolant meters and stuff, they do find them every now and then, but those
are on the customer side to replace the meter cans themselves. That's very equipment.
So if we go to replace these meters, the possible that the system might have to spend some money
to help us replace this? No, they would have to replace their equipment. That is their equipment
that's on the house, so it would be on them to replace that. Yes. That would be, I don't know,
what percentage do you think the home is very good to eat? It's going to be low percentage.
We run into that now. So I mean, what would happen now if we'd have that, it starts
arcing inside that meter in it over time and we'll start burning that up. So the problem will
already be there. We'll just be seeing that they have a problem, and it will keep them from having
a large, outage later where they have where they have to, it'd be in the middle of the night
where it would happen. On a weekend or something like that, we're actually people find some
of that stuff then, but the percentage of that, they didn't really give us a percentage of that,
but I do know some of the people I've talked to in the past, they have done these.
type of projects you do find a few of those. So I don't want you to think we're not going to find any of them.
So what happens, I'm going to play devil's app in here from us, what happens if we roll up on it on a year or
or a lady's house and go to change your can. She's on a fixed income, barely afford a medicine.
And we're going to change her meter out and now we're the bad guy because she has to replace her meter and she can't afford it.
We do that already today. So if Kevin's guys go and change her meter out, my guys go change her meter out.
We do that today and we find it, they would still be on them. There's really no change.
It's actually just preventative for being at an inconvenient time for them.
Well, I'm saying, if she doesn't have a problem, we have another problem.
And we're going to change this meter out and now it's going to cost a lot.
I don't know what they cost to change it out. If we want to box maybe.
I said that's a pair estimate.
So she's not had a problem.
We're going to change the meter out and now we're talking about a problem.
The same cost of three or four hundred bucks.
And she don't have three or four hundred bucks, so when I don't kind of power it up, I'm going to just fix it.
That's correct.
Is that something where we could maybe send an notification to them, say, hey, our system is indicating that there is fault.
Well, we couldn't kind of back on because then we know there's a problem.
And we'll be liable if we make happen.
If there's a fire hazard there, yes, we're not going to turn that back on.
Maya, if that lady came to for it, now we shut her off.
And nobody knows where the problem and tell we wouldn't change a meter out.
There have been instances where we have damaged the meter.
But one of that and that's on us.
But there's also instances where we pull them out and pull the jaws out with them because they're so corroded.
That's on the end.
So it's a case by case basis.
It really depends on the situation when we take that measure out.
It's hard to say how many of these will be the problem.
So, is there any way we can plan ahead in case something like that happens to where that situation rises.
Instead of cutting that customer off, if there are a way we can work with them on helping them get it fixed and added to their bail or something like that.
Because that way this 90-year-old lady's not stuck without a lot of power.
Yeah, we can work there.
And I mean, we won't have to do it for everybody.
But I just don't afraid that case might pop up.
So I'm not going to tell you what to do.
But how do you say you're not going to do it for everybody?
I cannot do it for everybody.
Well, if someone says I can't afford to fix that.
I'm saying I'm not going to shut them all.
Yeah, I mean, if they can afford it, they have to stand on that side.
But if it's not your lady, this is out with money.
I don't want to walk off labor with no power.
And I have to be right.
So, some of the cases.
It may not happen.
Yeah, some of the cases I know before I know some of the electricians do work with them and they take payment plans.
I do know that for a fact because I've seen it.
I mean, we'll just hope that doesn't happen and we don't have to see it, but well, but
something we can look into, I mean, see, we can put our options.
We can put it out for a bit now.
Could it be, to see if we can get those electricians to?
Oh yeah, we have an on-call price.
But the problem is we don't, as we don't want the responsibility to changing the can's up,
because that's their equipment.
And if we damage something else, we don't, I don't think we want to take the responsibility
of replacing the equipment.
If we're going to have some program where they, maybe they need to sign something or something
that waves us live away from us.
Because sometimes you get into some of that, and now they need to break or now they need this
reward.
Now they need this, because they haven't done the updates to the house.
And I don't know where you want that to stop.
You know what I mean?
Or could there be something or if this meter is unable to be changed at that time?
Like, we've got 90 days, we can give them like a time frame.
Leave the existing meter in there.
And then they have to be replaced.
But it has to be replaced.
But yeah.
It's hard to see that to you pull the meter out.
Yeah.
Unless they have, if they got half power, they have low voltage.
That's when we're finding these after hours, or during the day,
those emergency calls we get.
That's when we find them is when they've already run out like that.
Other than that, you can't see the inside of those meter cans,
where well, some of them you can't take the little off and look into them.
But some are still a base meter basis that,
it's literally the size of the meter.
There's no way to look at it, but you pull them out.
So I mean, it is unfortunate.
But it, the problem would be already on their side.
We're actually just exposing what it was,
and letting them know what that was.
We would, we always work with them the best we can.
If there's some way to put that back in and wait,
we would absolutely do that until we could.
But if it's like a set of it, the fire hazard,
we don't want to burn them around.
Yeah.
Also, you know, to remind the board this is,
you know, as a part of our rating crisis,
so this is what we raised the customer charge to build a part of the money to,
you know, pay for all these projects.
So I mean, this is a commutations.
We're excited.
I mean, I'm worried about the water meters that I have the electric meters,
and so pluses.
Obviously, I mean, we're up to the electric meters,
but that's what worries me, because I mean,
everybody knows the way that's had a water leak,
or whatever, because of the whole system.
So there's like a program that says things could,
like, something, or like an opt-in type of thing,
where they could maybe, let's say pay five extra dollar,
or there's something to develop, like,
I don't know, maybe this is something they should do with their own around.
But something for that case, so they're not.
And again, there's a low percentage,
and I get where pluses coming from,
because I wouldn't want to be hit with that,
and then also my power being turned off.
But also, I get where you guys are coming from.
We can't have that liability.
So like, how do you make those things happen?
Is that something we can maybe...
down at some point in kind of brainstorm. Yeah, we can change them out and just bring
some back to a work session like what they they ran into this and I mean. Yeah, but
how do they do it? Yeah, something like that. And well, I don't know. I don't want to
start this process down. I want you guys to keep going ahead, but maybe at the meantime we
can wear something out there because it's going to be a lot of work for X to start changing some
outside. The good news is the water meters were out of where we were nine, 10 months, a year
after we actually get in because I got a manufacturing of what we wanted to do. In the lead
time it is a long, long, long electric meters. It does not, that's not the case on the water
make that water meters. So we have some time to brainstorm on how we want to handle those situations.
I don't believe that we have kind of those cases, but I do believe that there'll be a few of those cases
that you don't have to upgrade their side. You know, and if it's something that we caused
like Kevin said, we have a uniform if it's something we've caused. You good? Yeah, okay. So this project
this, it has four components toward. We had 11 submittals on it, which was a really, really good
response we sat up there and went through them for a long time. That was the time about it. Yeah.
I would like to thank, it wasn't just me in Kevin. There was numerous people that
sat through those meetings to discuss the different parts of these for components that we did
like Tyler mentioned. We narrowed it down to four finalists to begin with. This first portion,
the first component was A and my fan, which is the field area network. We'll recommend here in a minute
to use Lansing gear. This is basically the water, the electric meter portion of that and what's out in the
field. It is also, they're one of the biggest in the company, and in the world, about in the electric
meters is Lansing gear. They have a lot of, they have a lot of power quality issues that we could use within
that's why we, it's one of the reasons we selected them, but this is mainly what that is, is the
electric meters in that portion of those. The second portion is the water meter portion. After we
went to, after we narrowed down to Lansing gear, we, it wasn't happy with, with their water solution
in the timelines I had on that. So we, we want to go with the cellular solution on that. So we, we went back
and looked at Neptune. And this, this will be the water portion will be the meters and cells, the
the lids and the antennas for that. So this will be F. Can you kind of tell them, Derek, which I
don't know would be. Okay, so yeah. Yeah, I was just going to do every one of them, but yeah, so that'd be F.
And one of the big things about them is that they are U.S. May, they have a very, very strong presence in
Oklahoma. They also have a multi-speak.
with their cellular, which means they have a failover.
If this cellular network goes down,
it's already in the radio, the modems that they go to
the cellular network.
And that is included in the price of what they do.
So it's a backup to the backup already in the modem.
And that's really good.
They are a ultrasonic meter that we went with,
which picks up low flow, so we will have some low flows
that we are picking up, which is better accuracy.
And they are all brass meter, and it's a really good meter.
The third portion, which would be, which is the next one,
I don't have the G or G.
It'd be G.
You'll notice here in just a second,
H will be working to the same person,
but G is the metadatum management system,
which is what all this information is coming into.
All the information from the electric meters and the water meters
are going to go into mdms, which it takes all that information.
It will distribute it out to the customer portal
and out to our billing software.
So it puts all that, the source, all that data from all those intervals
inside that, and that's how it talks back and forth.
It also has, I guess that's on the next one.
H, it would be for the corn main for their mdms,
which is the reason we're, or worrying that's because that's where they put their cellular charges
for their water meters.
They put it in the mdms.
It's not that we need their mdms.
It's that's where their cellular charges are.
So the cellular charges are in there.
Plus it had the Neptune 360, which is another way to talk to the water meters.
The last would be that, to be I, which would be the customer portal
and land is in gear had the best overall.
All of the things that we got to begin with as a committee was the customer portal.
Everybody on that committee thought that this customer portal was about.
And it's land is in gear, but they're seven that up to the X connect.
It does happen app, which I know you'll be happy to hear that they actually happen app
and the app store for that.
It is totally customizable.
We can put our logos on it.
We can change the colors up, but we can put what information we want to put on there.
Everyone's are low flow if they get signals for low water in their pipe.
If they get at or whatever that is, we can put that actually on that customer portal.
It will take that customer portal will have both electric and water in that same customer portal,
which was a really nice feature of that.
And the functionality of it, you could get like I said, you could totally customize how.
What we want that to look like.
So, you know, we have a different electric meter and a different water meter.
They both worked with this same customer portal.
Yes, so it's actually, I know the answer, but I wanted to talk to the answer.
Yes, it talks to the MDMS from Blanc and Gear, and that goes to the customer portal.
They pull that data.
That's how it gets it open.
You see that?
Then when they get on their app, they'll be able to see their electric meter and their water meter
on the same app.
That is correct.
Get them and start communicating, then you know, get them to communicate with app.
And then it's on it quick.
It's going to be a couple of year project.
So you've got to change out the water meters, or you've got a big app yard, or it's going to be able to plug and play.
Well, ideally, we wouldn't have to, but I'm sure there will be some meter tiles that we'll have to replace.
That will be on us.
It depends on what we find when we're there.
If we break their side, I'm sure we're going to have to do something with that.
Because you are moving pipes that's in the ground.
After there's going to be lots of maintenance caused by us being out there, it's just changing the meters out.
We've got to make sure the lids actually fit on the cans that are out there.
So if the cans don't fit, at the lids that we're getting don't fit those.
Because they're clear, they're paper or whatever they may be, or there's the, we may have to do some retrofitting for some of those down in the alleys, because they're got bigger lids and stuff like that on it.
Well, we do internal cell, cyberskiri, audits roll that we've done by third party.
The cyberskiri, I think it was part of their part of their part of their part.
Yeah, so they, okay.
So on this app, well, and I'm just going to run some things here, just so people can hear it at the third watching.
On their app, are they going to be able to pay their bill over that?
There is a possibility to do that, yes.
And they'll be able to see their water usage, and let's use daily hourly.
It depends on how we set that up, but yes, they will be able to see it in increments of, depends on how we put that information out there for them.
I mean, yes.
I don't know about the water, electrical, probably smaller intervals than what the, within what the water intervals are.
And the other highlights of it, that it sends alarms, like I said, if you have a hot socket on that ear, if you're at a power, if you have, if you're low flow, if there's a league detection,
it'll it'll send that out there.
It does what we, it depends on how we set that stuff out, and how the customers want that, what information they actually need to be wanting.
So if they believe they have a league, they'll get an notification saying, hey, you have a possible league.
It can, yes.
Well, something I learned from talking to, like, one of the contacts in Florida that we reached out to.
So these meters will pick up like a trip, you know, a lot of colder houses, or even near
our house, you know, you have a trip, you don't really think about it, because it's a truck
on your build, well they're so sensitive they show up that trip.
So they get like a, like Derek was saying, an email, maybe the customer is not checking in
their portal.
So then they'll go ahead and send the customer a letter in the mail saying, hey, you're pretty
out of the way, you know, you have the audio, you have the customer calls in, they'll say,
hey, we're showing you using like this amount of water versus how you've used in the past.
And so they can kind of say, oh, yeah, you have a leaky toilet or, you know, I mean,
it's just, you know, because there is ongoing costs with this.
I mean, it's everywhere is on my meters, but there is some ongoing costs that you bother me.
But you know, everybody I talked to, it's almost like just the information that you have a hand to
talk to the customer with is worth the ongoing costs.
But I mean, that gives the opportunity to stop that leak within a month, rather than six months.
And for that customer, so we're doing an offer to help them save some money.
So, so if these are a fruit tonight, then we would put out for the changing out of the water
meters, because I don't know if we have enough people to change out all our water meters.
So we didn't say, bring that back to the board, and then obviously barring the money for the
part that's not covered by the grants.
So just let everybody kind of know the timeline and everything, but I'm excited.
I mean, say, huge, huge project, I mean, so it tells about the grant part a little bit.
So we got a grant, we partnered with a motocs and the Ottawa tribe for a matching grant,
or for a tribal grant.
And so this, the 3.4 million will go towards AMI and the water treatment plant.
So we're very thankful to our tribal partners.
You know, wasn't I reach out to them when we found out about it, and they were very happy
which is to be with us.
And I mean, we're very thankful for everyone that we kicked off the water treatment plant.
For everybody to start, we can have a huge photo off in the mean.
So this was a $3.4 million grant.
Yep.
Okay.
And then last one that they're going to go through, but the resolution kind of speeds
up that process was missing.
I can't really, I did, you know, we did that way.
We could, because it is our reporting, so you know, there is a deadline.
So we're trying to get things ordered and move this fast as we can.
So we need these to vote it on feet, individually.
Yes.
Any other questions for Derek or Tyler or Mr. Irmig.
You know, so we're looking for a motion on 5E for the electric meters.
And then we're going to land us a year.
Our staff recommendation would be that you would award the bid for the fancetering infrastructure
A.M.I. fan network to land us a year to authorize the trust manager to negotiate and execute
those contracts.
And this is for 5E.
Yes.
Every for all of them, just a different vendor for all of them.
Yeah.
All right.
and motion for five F water meters and authorized the trust major to negotiate contract and consent and execute the contract.
5G warded a bit to Lannis a year and approved the C manager to negotiate and execute the contract.
Trust manager?
Yes.
You said city manager?
Trust manager?
Yes.
I don't know.
It's just that.
Five Hs.
To ward a bit to Corman.
Yes.
And authorized the trust manager to negotiate and execute the contract.
Motion for five.
5.
Five of the course council postpains?
Five.
5.
bid documents for advanced meeting infrastructure projects and successfully successful bid
biders prices obtained all necessary approvals and execute contracts with the successor bid
vendors previously selected on November 13th, 2025.
So this just qualifies what you've just done in which is previous negotiating, you can go over the amount
that we're in the bid, but he might be able to get it out of here.
All right.
5K award rebid for water treatment plant improvements to work and structure and corporate
rate to include bid alternative A4, not to exceed 2,100, 2 million, 1,37,930 dollars, and
authorize the trust manager to sign the contract contingent upon a legal review and Oklahoma
Water Resources Board Approase.
So, this is that water treatment plant that we was talking about earlier.
We went up for bid earlier and it came in really high, it came in 2.6 million.
And we, the regular bid came in at 2 million, 2.990, 30, with that alternate for the bigger generator is the one all of them that we're asking to put on there.
This will be for all the pumps, although the piping, the valves, redoing the clear room, the clear well itself, all that piping that's in there we did go in there this last year and we cleaned the inside of that and all that has it been touched inside there since it was built.
I mean it's all those valves need to be redone.
So, to be all that valves, the piping outside and those pumps, the VFDs, the motor controls that will actually run those pumps and motors.
So, how long we talking, how long we talking to do it?
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's a year and a day.
Will it be any eruptions on the water?
There should be no interruptions on the water.
This thing, we don't want that, I guess you understand.
I understand.
We don't.
Yeah.
But, so that is.
And we don't want a commerce situation either.
Well, that's why I figured she was going with that.
But that is.
So, in that plant.
Right now, you can send water two different ways.
We have other sources of water besides just to clear well.
And when everything's going well, we can't operate without it at all.
But it's like we have no redundancy at that point if something else would fail.
But in that plant, we can, like I said this last year, we actually took the clear well down for about two weeks.
And it wasn't using it at all.
There will be some staged places in there.
Where we will be down.
But we will be able to pump water.
There's two ways that can pump water out of that facility.
It can go out the south end with a north end.
But when we have the clear well down, we will have to, there's actually two sides.
So that's if we can actually do one side, we can get a valve shut,
so there's a ways to isolate that.
That's what we've had problems with in the past is not being able to do.
I select that that we will.
Because all the stuff is.
So, no, we do not plan on doing that if we have to get it back up.
We can get back up to what we'll have to have a plan to be able to stop construction, fill it back up and start producing water out of there.
What I've learned about water is it is almost going to happen.
It is very unpredictable.
In your package, if you've been on the page 286, you can see some of the type in that will be replaced.
He's a little bit sad.
Too many things?
He's a 286 dollar.
Too many things.
I'm sure we've got some.
Balls are old.
Yeah, you still haven't found it.
How did you get there?
He's going the wrong way.
I am.
No, no.
You're just looking at mine.
I will.
Thank you.
Where's this at?
This is OPC.
It's in the big tall white building.
Since I'm there.
It's actually on the West End and that.
I was just piping down there.
Since it was put in there.
I don't know who was that built in the 1920s.
I don't know.
All right.
Thank you guys.
Thank you.
Sixth.
A presentation and discussion of main 66.
Then you located at 116 North Main.
Brenda.
Two hundred.
Thank you.
Good evening.
I'm excited.
You're welcome.
I don't even understand any of this.
I don't.
Thank you.
I'm excited to bring to you the evening plans for the former main attractions building at 116 North Main.
It is a hundred year old structure.
It was built in 1925 originally as a typewriter repair and sales place.
So think about that.
We don't even have them now.
So that's how cool they needed a store to do that.
So that's kind of fun.
Tyler asked us when we were doing the budget a year ago to be mindful of every department and to find ways to be able to help our departments make some money.
Some money.
So I begin thinking about Miami Main Street and that we a lot of times have to have fundraisers along the way to help support that program.
So this would be a way to fund partially fund that program on a consistent basis.
The thought is to have a venue, a small venue that you could rent.
There's a capacity of only 75 people in that building.
The city has been renting it out for several months and been just kind of by word of mouth.
And so right before Christmas Kevin sort of gave that to the CVB office to take over renting.
And we already have rentals for March.
We have four rentals for March. We have one for December of 2026 and then we have a birthday party next weekend.
So by word of mouth we've already gotten that much.
You have in your packet remodel costs for the building.
The city has fixed the heat and air situation that was happening.
They've also put taking care of the roof so it doesn't leak anymore.
But because it was leaking there were some repairs that needed to be done to the wall.
They're needed some scraping and painting that is done.
So the remodel costs are, as you see there, facilities will cover and paint the wall and repair them as needed.
And this includes any spackle and drywall and mud to protect them and then the tools needed to repaint it.
The sign on the front of the building we would like to call this venue main 66 venue.
And we would like to take the interior much back to like the 1925 era of decorating to bring it kind of up to a unique capacity.
I'm allowed to show this to you if you want to paste.
I'm very visual.
That's a project word.
Colors what our paints watch is on it.
It includes paintings a little bit more lighting in it with some wallpaper behind it.
Ordering some chairs.
I would love to be able to put an ice machine in there because that's like the pits.
I have to carry ice everywhere when you rent a facility.
My Emma Main Street.
My Emma Main Street would take care of all the paperwork and the rentals for the building.
We would collect the fees and get them deposited.
We would do the cleaning after each event is held.
We're going to ask that the renters leave the facility as they find it.
Occasionally there that won't be what happens and so we need to go over there and and take care of it
And there is a hundred dollar deposit that they'll get back if they leave it in good shape
Yeah, it's in your packet on the there's if we go with everything it's about
$95
My there is an alarm system and Main Street will take care of that fee yearly fee in the
city we have lost
Venue 29 it's no longer
Available and we've also lost the family center for at Paul Thomas so there's no smaller venue to be able to rent just for a small
Gathering
I believe on the second page in your packet. There's a rental fee proposal
For nights and weekends and then there would be a percentage that would go to my MMA Main Street in a percentage that would go to
MSUAS and stay on the building
Currently the building is sitting in between all the times that we rent it out
Any any usage by the city would be free and
We just need to be booked through our office. So the city could use it for heritage fest or a meeting or
The mayor's conference or whatever
Came up for the city. Yes
It was also the best station in Miami for a while to yeah, and across the city the guy that owned it his wife owned a music store
Consistency for her office is now
Maybe
Didn't you maybe think about putting Friday down as one of the weekend days? Yes, yeah, we would
Yes, so it would be Friday through Sunday would be our weekend rent rates
Not just Saturday and Sunday and that will actually include holidays also so we would up that
So the sign
Are you asking us to pick us under the
Four different G if you would like to tell me which one you'd like that would be fine. I know which one I like, but
Yeah, this one
Yeah, so would it be me on
Yes, it has like what I call golf club lights because I live just like golf club is inverted and they're there existing already
I like I like the theme. I think that's fun
So I like I said like came
It's beautiful
She wins Christmas every year
Do you all have any other questions or
So this is
I'll be honest with you. I think I was honest to cheat
Okay, I'm so big
There when we read it on a free schedule because there was no improvements to the building
We were just trying to get promoted at a larger scale of what we did on the end to it. It will be a few reasons
I think it's T.C.
It's education
We want to educate the board to see people working on it
So this is something where once it's ready
We can start
Just smack it everywhere
Yes, so it's like we're coming
Once it's ready
We should do more of our council meetings there
We can
Can I show it off to the community that way
That'd be awesome
Art's kind of the target
If we can get everything ordered and there are no bumps
We'll do we're kind of looking at March 1st
To be able to
They've already been working on it
They haven't been there
They didn't. Yes, they'll pay
They'll probably this week
It's ready
It's primed and it's re-textureed and it's, thanks, that work.
Thank you.
So another new business, I say many, which is the reason since the post of this agenda.
Hey, trustee, community management.
Nine trust management communications.
I just just let them order now.
We open beds on our, this one.
So open beds on materials and then on construction.
I'm just out of our bed back.
If anybody's watching, I'd like to bed on it.
And I would gather some people to there.
That's what we did.
We're going to make some, which is cool as a group.
I mean, we're going to make some significant improvements in our infrastructure for the community.
So I mean, there can't be, it might be very few times in the city's history.
There'll be more money spent on infrastructure.
What's this building?
Yeah.
10 through 16 will not be needed.
We will not be going to executive session.
So 17 adjournment.
Motion.
Thank you.
Bye.